Mubarak Ali Alghanim

0

Al Khobar, Eastern, Saudi Arabia



+966 56 875 8388



mubarak_al-ghanem@hotmail.com



linkedin.com/in/mubarak-alghanim-845691194



About Me

A Bachelor of Science Degree in Computer Information Systems (CIS) holder with two years of professional experience. Accredited as Computer Science Specialist by the Saudi Council of Engineers (SCE). Self-motivated and ambitious to be a professional specialist or analyst in computer information systems, data science, or any related IT field with the ability to commit, innovate, and hard work to evolve and learn to gain knowledge and skills to improve my expertise and apply them in the working processes. Interested to develop my skills in information technology, information system, cybersecurity, data analysis, systems analysis, and programming by reading articles, attending courses and webinars, and practicing.



Education

Bachelor of Science Degree in Computer Information System (CIS) | King Faisal University (KFU)

From August 2014 to January 2020

With a Very Good Grade and a GPA is (4.07) Out of (5).



Courses and Bootcamps

Cybersecurity Training Initiative Program (CyberPro - Beginner Level) | National Cybersecurity Authority (NCA) From January 2020 to February 2020

Al Summer Champions Program (Data Engineering Foundation Path) | Saudi Authority for Data and Artificial Intelligence (SDAIA)

From July 2022 to October 2022



Professional Accreditation

Computer Science Specialist (CSS) | Saudi Council of Engineers (SCE)

Accredited in March 2021 - Expire in March 2024

Accreditation ID: 750149.

Accreditation Type: Allied Engineering Specialist.



Professional Certifications

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate (V2) | Authorized by IBM & Powered by Coursera

Issued in October 2021

Credential ID: 325cb406-59a6-40c4-9b8d-2b9bfcf087da.

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2021 Associate | Oracle

Issued in December 2021 - Expire in June 2023

Credential ID: 2886897520CIBF2021.

Google Data Analytics Certificate 2022 | Authorized by Google & Powered by Coursera

Issued in March 2022

Credential ID: 9e09ad25-12e4-4782-9d96-02c99a627f14.

RapidMiner - Data Engineering Professional Certification | RapidMiner

Issued in August 2022

Credential ID: da3f3abf-79d4-4af1-a2d0-3325780e1a4d.



- Data Analysis
- Systems Analysis
- System Administration
- Programming (Java SE, Python, C#, and SQL)
- Data Entry
- Microsoft Office
- IT Management
- Software Development (Agile and Waterfall methodologies, Use Case, DFD, ERD, and UML)
- Oracle Cloud
- Technical Support
- Time Management
- Multitasking



Work Experience

Information Technology (IT) Officer | Gulf Lifting Financial Leasing (GLFL) Company | Full Time

From March 2021 to July 2022

City: Dammam, Eastern, Saudi Arabia

Job Responsibilities:

- Offering technical support to company staff and troubleshooting computer problems.
- Installing, configuring, and updating company software and hardware.
- Managing Avaya Telephones through updating the extension, resetting the settings, and adding a new extension.
- Responsible for submission or retake of the IT assets to\from employees.
- Downloading Kastle and Orion systems backup files from the server and uploading them into oracle cloud & Hard Disk.
- Managing company backups through Veeam Backup & Replication tool by creating auto-backup jobs, backup storage, and backup agents.
- Checking the Cybersecurity Threat Advisory Report from Saudi Central Bank (SAMA) to identify the risks that the company's devices or employees will be facing and trying to avoid the risk such as phishing emails, social engineering, etc...
- Checking Sophos Firewall to find any suspicious cases in the network, blocking suspicious IP addresses, and applying policies such as blocking USB ports and isolating a device from the network.
- Managing emails through Microsoft Admin Center by creating or blocking access, creating groups, licenses management, recovering emails, and releasing emails from the quarantined messages.
- Monitoring the network through Fore-scout to protect sensitive information, secure access to resources, and demonstrate compliance.
- Reporting through an excel sheet to the head of the department about devices information, availability, user, and status, software usage, number of POs that have been made, number of delivery notes with items that have been received, applications backups status, and number of the available licenses of Microsoft Office at the beginning of every month.
- Designing a Flowchart diagram to explain the functions of the new system to the project team.
- Working with the project team to enter the system data into Excel sheets for the data integration and migration stage.

Java Developer & Information Technology Specialist | King Fahad Hospital | Internship

From April 2019 to August 2019

City: Al Hufūf, Eastern, Saudi Arabia

It is a cooperative training course between the college and the Ministry of Health, and I worked as a Co-op trainee for five months in the hospital.

Job Responsibilities:

- Contributing to all phases of the application development lifecycle.
- Conducting software analysis, programming, testing, and debugging.
- Ensuring designs comply with specifications.
- Offering technical support to hospital staff and troubleshooting computer problems.
- Installing, configuring, and updating hospital computer software, hardware, printers, and scanners.



Car Diagnosis System (CDS) | King Faisal University | Graduation Project

Started in January 2019 - Completed in January 2020

Description: The Car Diagnosis System (CDS) is an expert system that can assist the user in dealing with his/her car problems by showing basic categories of car problems and the user will choose one of them then the system will ask the user multiple questions to identify the specific problem. After that, it will show a problem diagnosis for the problem based on the user's answers. Finally, the system will show a problem solution in a video to solve the problem. The CDS was developed by using Java ME as a programming language through the android system and MySQL as a database.

Artificial Limb Submission System (ALSS) | King Fahad Hospital | Internship Project

Started in April 2019 - Completed in July 2019

Description: The Artificial Limb Submission System (ALSS) is a system that automates the process of submitting an artificial limb to the patients by recording each process of the submissions in the database with special specifications related to the data for patients and artificial limbs. The ALSS was developed by using Java SE as the programming language and Microsoft Access as the database.

IT Assets System (ITAS) | Gulf Lifting Financial Leasing (GLFL) Company | Work Project

Started in June 2021 - Completed in July 2021

Description: The IT Assets System (ITAS) is a collection of IT assets like PCs, monitors, laptops, printers, and phones with their descriptions, serial number, and users had been registered in a spreadsheet that will be used later to attach the IT assets by tag labels (barcode). The tag labels have been designed using Zebra Designer and printed using Zebra GK420d Thermal Printer.